Student Religious Organizations Records, 1892-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Student Religious Organizations Records
1892-[ongoing]
Student Religious Organizations 1892-[ongoing]
RG 80
18 boxes (9 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Contains minutes, correspondence, memos, photographs, printed material and general material related to student religious organizations at Smith College.
Historical Note
The Smith College Association for Christian Work (SCACW) was founded in 1892. It was designed, according to its constitution, "to promote the development of a broad and intelligent activity in the cause of humanity and to unite in one central body the organizations already existing in the college and those to be formed in future for the purpose of active Christian work." By 1953, the organization is identified as the Smith College Religious Association (SCRA), and is referred to as an 'interfaith' organization. Today this area of student life is referred to as Religious and Spiritual Life, and encompasses many different faiths and worshipping communities.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
These records consist primarily of records of the Smith College Association for Christian Work and the Smith College Religious Association, the two largest identities of the religious organizations of Smith College's history. Types of materials include chapel correspondence, information on retreats and conferences, activities and services, committee minutes, press releases, announcements, reports, financial information, and photographs. The most recent records reflect the growing diversity of the college community and its varying faiths.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into four series:
SERIES I. RELIGIOUS ORGANIZATIONS, A-Z, 1980s-1990s
SERIES II. SMITH COLLEGE ASSOCIATION FOR CHRISTIAN WORK (SCACW), 1892-1977
SERIES III. SMITH COLLEGE RELIGIOUS ASSOCIATION (SCRA), 1941-1977
SERIES IV. RELIGIOUS SERVICES, 1886-2002
OVERSIZE MATERIALS
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives except where noted in the finding aid.
Periodic additions to collection are expected and may not be reflected in this finding aid.
The records of the Student Religious Organizations were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Series I. Religious Organizations, A-Z, 1980s-1990s
  - Bahai c. 1990s (Box 1)
  - Campus Crusade for Christ c. 1990s (Box 1)
  - Christian Fellowship 1987 (Box 1)
  - Episcopal Fellowship 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Keystone 1988-1994 (Box 1)
  - Newman Association 1937-1988 (Box 1)
    - General n.d. (Box 1)
    - News clippings, press releases 1937-1968 (Box 1)
    - Events, general 1947-1994 (Box 1)
    - Events, New England Catholic College Association Symposium
      - News clippings 1988 (Box 1)
      - Evaluation form 1988 (Box 1)
      - Liturgy 1988 (Box 1)
      - Planning, correspondence 1987-1988 (Box 1)
      - Programs 1988 (Box 1)
      - Registration materials 1988 (Box 1)
      - Report 1987 (Box 1)
      - Thank you letters 1988 (Box 1)
  - Non-Smith Organizations and Associations
    - General 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - NECCA 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Orders of Worship 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Photographs 1939-1993 (Box 1)
  - Smith Christian Fellowship 1992 (Box 1)
- Series II. Smith College Association for Christian Work (SCACW), 1892-1977
  - A
    - Advisory Committee, General 1901-1940 (Box 2)
    - Advisory Committee, Meeting Minutes 1902-1914 (Box 2)
    - Advisory Committee, Meeting Minutes 1914-1943 (Box 2)
    - Advisory Committee, Meeting Minutes 1944-1965 (Box 2)
    - Alumnae Auxiliary Printed material 1913-1932 (Box 2)
    - Anti-War Activities announcements, press releases 1934, 1935, n.d. (Box 2)
  - B
    - Bible classes, announcements, schedules 1903-1919 (Box 2)
    - Bible Study Committee reports 1903-1927 (Box 2)
  - C
    - Cabinet, General: Cabinet policies, cabinet member lists, announcements 1913-1944 (Box 3)
    - Cabinet, Meeting Minutes 1930s (Box 3)
    - Charities: Shingling House, Pine Mountain Settlement School, Berea College, Caney Creek Community Center and Homesteads, miscellaneous 1918-1942 (Box 3)
    - Christian Union Meeting announcements 1902 (Box 3)
    - Church Cooperation: Correspondence, pamphlets, press releases, <titlerender="italic">The Westminsterite newsletter of the Presbyterian Student Center 1920s-1940s (Box 3)
    - College Settlements: letter from Grace Hubbard to Mrs. Wells, Pamphlets from Denison House, Boston and University Settlement annual reports 1904, 1927, 1930 (Box 3)
    - Community Chest: Press releases, announcements, photograph 1930-1940 (Box 3)
    - Community Service: Press releases, notes, entertainment committee notes 1929-1939 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, General 1920-1940 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Freshman: Press releases, program outlines, correspondence 1926-1940 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Interfaith: Press releases, seminars, correspondence 1929-1941 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Northfield (YWCA affiliated): Group photographs, conference reports, programs 1897-1939 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Silver Bay (YWCA affiliated): Pamphlets, daily bulletins, conference newspaper <titlerender="italic">The Pick-Up 1903-1935 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Silver Bay: Photographs 1902-1929 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Silver Bay: Photographs 1902-1929 (Box 3)
    - Conferences, Summer (Camp O-At-Ka): Pamphlets, correspondence, press releases 1938-1940 (Box 3)
    - Constitutions and By-Laws 1892-1920s? (Box 3)
  - D
    - Day Book 1903-1904 (Box 4)
    - Deputations: Reports, correspondence, press releases 1924-1938 (Box 4)
    - Discussion Groups: Notes, clippings, press releases 1916-1941 (Box 4)
  - F
    - Finances - Funds, Alice Duryee Memorial Fund: Treasurer's reports 1925-1954 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Funds, Alice Jackson Memorial Fund: Treasurer's reports, history 1908-1954 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Funds, General: Account information, reports, correspondence 1912-1955 (Box 4)
    - Finances - General: Statements, miscellaneous 1931-1941 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Gifts: Correspondence and acknowledgements regarding gifts given and received 1920-1965 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Treasurer: Budget statements 1927-1938 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Treasurer, Account Book 1893-1921 (Box 4)
    - Finances - Treasurer, Account Book 1915-1923 (Box 4)
    - Foreign Students: Chinese students, German refugees, miscellaneous 1921-1948 (Box 4)
    - Foreign Students: Photographs 1921-1947 (Box 4)
    - Forums - Marriage Forums: Lecture announcements, press releases, newspaper clippings 1938-1939 (Box 4)
    - Forums - Religious Forums: Reports of the Religious Services Department, speaker program information, press releases, announcements 1921-1957 (Box 4)
  - G
    - General 1901-1940 (Box 5)
    - General - Other Colleges 1901-1976 (Box 5)
    - Guest Book 1915 (Box 5)
  - H
    - Handbooks
      - President's 1936-1944 (Box 5)
      - Vice President's 1913-1920 (Box 5)
    - History 1940, n.d. (Box 5)
  - L
    - Lectures: Announcements, press releases 1929-1938 (Box 5)
    - Loan Library 1917-1930s (Box 5)
  - M
    - Membership Activities 1912-1944 (Box 5)
    - Membership Records 1905-1906 (Box 6)
    - Membership Records 1906-1907 (Box 6)
    - Membership Records 1907-1908 (Box 6)
    - Minutes and reports 1892-1899 (Box 7)
    - Minutes and reports 1899-1902 (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1902-1905 (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1905-1909 (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1909-1916 (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1915-1923 (Box 7)
    - Minutes 1923-1930 (Box 8)
    - Minutes 1930-1936 (Box 8)
    - Mission Study Classes 1901-1917 (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: Constitution n.d. (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: General, reports, financial papers 1901-1917 (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: Miscellaneous 1891-1926 (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: Myers, Angie Martin, Dr.
      - Biographical 1908, 1939 (Box 8)
      - Correspondence 1900-1901 (Box 8)
      - Photographs of China 1902- (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: Reports, correspondence with Dewitt Baldwin 1936-1938 (Box 8)
    - Missionary Society: Secretary's records 1876-1902 (Box 8)
  - N
    - National Collegiate Christian Council: General, reports 1938-1945 (Box 8)
    - Needlework Guild: One letter from Alice Gibson to B.F. Briggs (both class of 1898) n.d. (Box 8)
  - O
    - Organization: Officers, list of presidents, etc. c. 1920-1939 (Box 9)
  - P
    - Peace n.d., [See also Smith College Religious Association]
    - People's Institute 1942 (Box 9)
      [See Northampton History Collection]
    - Photographs 1928-1940 (Box 9)
    - Prayer Meetings: Notices, topics 1893-1901 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1903-1904 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1905-1906 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1906-1907 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1907-1908 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1908-1909 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1909-1910 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1910-1911 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1911-1912 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1912-1913 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1913-1914 (Box 9)
    - President's Journal 1914-1915 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1915-1916 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1916-1917 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1917-1918 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1918-1919 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1919-1920 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1920-1921 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1922-1923 (Box 10)
    - President's Journal 1923-1924 (Box 10)
  - R
    - Ramabai Association 1887-1901 (Box 10)
    - Race Relations, General: YWCA material 1937-1939 (Box 10)
    - Race Relations, Inter-race Committee Pamphlets, press releases, announcements 1939-1951 (Box 10)
    - Rabbit Hollow: Clippings, press releases, announcements 1954-1955 (Box 10)
    - Relief, Refugee Relief: Reports, statements, letters 1938, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Reports 1901-1904 (Box 10)
    - Reports, Annual Reports 1900-1910 (Box 11)
    - Reports, Annual Reports 1911-1922 (Box 11)
    - Reports, Annual Reports 1922-1944 (Box 11)
    - Reports, General Secretary 1901-1941 (Box 11)
    - Reports, House of Representatives: Includes Publicity Committee 1917-1941 (Box 11)
    - Reports, Vice President 1929-1934 (Box 11)
    - Reports, Treasurer n.d., [SEE FINANCES] (Box 11)
  - S
    - Self Help Bureau: Financial aid advice, information 1918-1919 (Box 11)
    - Self Help Bureau: Christmas Seal Sale 1915-1940 (Box 11)
    - Social Services: Reports 1925-1938 (Box 11)
    - Student Christian Movement: Program schedules, newsletters 1938-1944 (Box 12)
    - Student Christian Movement: History, constitutions, press releases, mission statements, reports, correspondence, memos, minutes 1933-1955 (Box 12)
    - Student Handbook 1899-1939 (Box 12)
    - Student Industrial Committee: Reports, memos, minimum wage information 1924-1938 (Box 12)
    - Student Volunteer Band (Evangelization): Letters, constitutions, reports, "Christian Voices Around the World" questionnaires, Pamphlets 1910-1931 (Box 12)
    - Student Volunteer Band (Evangelization): Record Book [removed from rotted binding, blank pages discarded] 1906-1910 (Box 12)
    - Student Volunteer Band (Evangelization): Western Massachusetts Volunteer Union, Record Book 1897-1906 (Box 12)
    - Student Volunteer Band (Evangelization): Minutes 1910-1914 (Box 12)
    - Summer Session: Farming and other activities and work 1944 (Box 12)
  - T
    - Trustees: Correspondence, memos 1911-1954 (Box 12)
    - Trustees, Notebook: Finances, annual reports, funds 1911-1945 (Box 12)
  - V
    - Vacations Services: Pamphlets, programs, etc about retreats, vacation houses 1928-1950 (Box 13)
  - W
    - War Work: <titlerender="italic">Public Affairs News Service bulletins; miscellaneous notes, reports 1942-1945 (Box 13)
    - Week of Prayer: Dr Calkins photograph, prayer meetings, chapel prayers 1897-1929 (Box 13)
    - Welcome to entering students: Social Committee report, welcome letters, press releases 1901-1940 (Box 13)
    - World Student Christian Fellowship: Course schedules, pamphlets, bulletins, press releases 1918-1944 (Box 13)
  - Y
    - YWCA: Student Council memos, official correspondence 1927-1954 (Box 13)
- Series III. Smith College Religious Association (SCRA), 1941-2002
  - A
    - African Scholarships: General correspondence, memos 1957-1960 (Box 14)
    - African Scholarships: Florence Mwangi correspondence 1956-1959 (Box 14)
    - African Scholarships: James H. Robinson correspondence 1956-1959 (Box 14)
    - African Scholarships Funds: Ada N. Leffingwell 1957 (Box 14)
    - African Scholarships Funds: United Church Women of New Jersey 1957-1958 (Box 14)
    - African Scholarships: Institute of African-American Relations correspondence 1957-1959 (Box 14)
  - C
    - Charter and Constitution 1953-1964 (Box 14)
    - Christian Association, Cevenol Work Camp 1954-1956 (Box 14)
    - Christian Association, Dagadu, Peter, Rev. 1957, 1960 (Box 14)
    - Christian Association, General 1951-1969 (Box 14)
    - Christian Council, Minutes 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - D
    - Danforth Intern, Priscilla Burton 1959-1963 (Box 14)
    - Drug Control 1968 (Box 14)
  - G
    - General: Clippings, member lists, press releases 1953-1977 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1954 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1955-1956 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1956-1957 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1958-1959 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1959-1960 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1960-1961 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1961-1962 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1962-1963 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, Chapel 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Hillel Foundation
    - B'nai B'rith 1977-1978 (Box 15a)
    - Smith College 1994-2002 (Box 15a)
    - Hillel at Noon 1996-1997, 2000 (Box 15a)
    - General 1954-1997 (Box 15a)
    - Jewish Organizations 1953-1971 (Box 15a)
    - Minutes and Memoranda 1997-1998 (Box 15a)
    - Minutes and Memoranda 1998-1999 (Box 15a)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1942, 1957-1994 (Box 15a)
    - Passover Haggadoh Programs 1995, 1998-2002 (Box 15a)
    - Newsletter 1945-2002 (Box 15a)
    - Photographs 1980-1995 (Box 15a)
    - Press Releases 1949-1970 (Box 15a)
    - Purim play (untitled) n.d. (Box 15a)
    - Selihot 1998 (Box 15a)
    - Siddur 1998 (Box 15a)
  - H
    - Human Relations workshop 1971 (Box 16)
  - I
    - Interdenominational Protestant Community 1994 (Box 16)
    - Interfaith Association: General, pamphlets, press releases, constitution, calendar, member lists 1945-1957 (Box 16)
    - Interfaith Association: Newspaper clippings 1948-1958 (Box 16)
    - Interfaith Association: President's notebooks 1955-1956 (Box 16)
    - Interrace Club 1953 (Box 16)
  - N
    - Newspaper clippings and Press releases 1946-1968 (Box 16)
  - P
    - Peace Commission: Policies, reports, memos, press releases, printed material 1923-1941 (Box 16)
    - Peace Corps: Press releases, printed material, newspaper clippings 1960-1966 (Box 16)
    - Photographs: Group photos, Freshman Picnic, Workday, student leaders 1952-1965 (Box 16)
    - Protestant Christian Association: Memos 1963-1964 (Box 16)
    - Protestant Christian Association Publications: <titlerender="italic">Perspective 1954-1959 (Box 16)
  - R
    - Religious Center 1952-1953 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Announcements, programs, schedules 1949-1954 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Correspondence, address of Paul Ramsey, programs 1954-1955 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Announcements, programs, correspondence, Memos, addresses of Canon Bryan Green. 1954-1956 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Announcements, programs, correspondence 1956-1957 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Correspondence, programs 1957-1958 (Box 16)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Correspondence, schedules 1958-1959 (Box 17)
    - Religious Forums (Interfaith Association): Newspaper clippings, press releases, programs 1959-1969 (Box 17)
  - S
    - Student Christian Movement
      - Correspondence, newsletters, retreats, schedules 1954-1955 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, retreats, schedules, photograph, programs, printed material 1955-1956 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, reports, printed material 1956-1957 (Box 17)
      - Report 1957-1958 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, memos, minutes, reports 1958-1959 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, memos, minutes, reports 1959-1960 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, memos, minutes, reports 1960-1961 (Box 17)
    - Student Conference: Correspondence, memos, pamphlets 1954-1956 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1953-1954 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1954-1955 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1955-1956 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1956-1957 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1957-1958 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1958-1959 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1959-1960 (Box 17)
    - Student Correspondence with Richard P. Unsworth 1960-1961 (Box 17)
    - Student Miscellaneous: Student lists, foreign student lists 1955-1958 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1954-1955 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1955-1956 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1956-1957 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1957-1958 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1958-1959 (Box 17)
    - Student Recommendations 1959-1960 (Box 17)
    - Work Day: Students do odd jobs to raise money for scholarships, loans, grants to students in need, often associated with the World University Service. Correspondence, photograph, announcements 1958-1964 (Box 17)
- Series IV: Religious Services, 1886-2002
  - Chapel, general 1886-1950 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1950-1958 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1959-1961 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1961-1962 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1970-1972 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1972-1973 (Box 18)
  - Morning worship, Helen Hills Hills Chapel 1973 (Box 18)
  - First Chapel: some photographs 1915-1946 (Box 18)
  - Speakers 1927-1936 (Box 18)
  - Speakers 1937-1938 (Box 18)
  - Speakers 1939-1990 (Box 18)
  - Special Services 1919-1970 (Box 18)
  - Vespers, programs 1900-1920 (Box 18)
  - Vespers, programs 1921-1949 (Box 18)
  - Vespers, programs 1950-2002 (Box 18)
- Oversize
  - Smith College Monthly clippings related to SCACW various (Map-case Flat file)
  - Peace corps posters, lecture announcements 1950s-1960s (Map-case Flat file)